## Jared Ryan

jryantennis@gmail.com | (559) 348-3595 | jaredryanwork.space | github.com/jaredryan

### Summary

Full stack software engineer specializing in React.js and Node.js. Front end lead of the user and role management service in IBM's data and Al analytics platform. Open to relocation.

Skills: JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, Python, Java, Ruby

### Experience

#### IBM, Cloud Pak for Data Software Developer II

San Jose, CA

Apr 2019 - Present

- Led front end development in React.js for user and role management for Cloud Pak for Data, a data and Al analytics platform
- Co-created conceptual models and user flows with design, providing guidance on attributes and relationships between users, roles, permissions, and groups
- Architected technical solutions with product and backend, considering security, performance, sizing, business value, and usability
- Built backend audit logging in Node.js for user and role management, for compliance and customer support
- Mentored and led product innovations teams, which produced 4 patent applications and 1 issued patent

#### IBM, AppID Software Developer I

Austin, TX

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

- Junior developer on ApplD, which helps developers easily add security to their apps
  - Prototyped a fullstack application in React, Node, and Python showcasing all uses of ApplD, and was leveraged for sales pitches and demos
  - Adapted to multiple technologies to quickly debug issues: OAuth, OpenID, Node, Angular, Java, Android, Swift, Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Github, Zenhub

# Negotiation and Team Resources Institute Web Developer

Berkeley, CA

Apr 2018 - Present

- Sole developer on a web app for collecting, grading, and anonymizing peer feedback, which has been used by 600 students, across 7 schools, generating 6K evaluations
- Collaborated with UC Berkeley professor to define product requirements and designs
- Addressed client and user issues through discussion, collaboration, then implementation
- Created data visualizations to show grades against class benchmarks

Site: https://negotiationfeedback.herokuapp.com | Code: github.com/jaredryan/peer-review

#### Education

UC Berkeley College of Engineering

Dec 2017

B.S. Bioengineering, Computer Science emphasis